Ruben Wilson

Software Engineer

London 07722160086 rwilson connell@yahoo.com

GitHub: https://github.com/ruben-wilson Website: https://ruben-wilson.netlify.app/

Summary

A twenty-one-year-old developer who is highly enthusiastic and driven. After spending nearly two years of my life preparing for the Marines, I never expected to find myself excited to start something new. Sustaining an injury in the Royal Marine's commando training, I was left with a fractured shoulder and I needed to find intellectual and physical stimulation which would fulfil my thirst for a challenge and importantly, also provide me with qualifications for a profession in which I would enjoy and be successful in.

Reconnecting with my love for technology and coding has been a very rewarding journey and I am very grateful for the path I am now on. I look forward to where this road will take me and embrace the challenge of being a part of this most exciting and innovative sector, which is technology.

Strong problem-solving and numerical skills.

Strong written and verbal communication developed through education and customer-facing experience gained in previous jobs.

Ability to take the initiative and work well under pressure, ensuring strict deadlines are met.

- · Strong team player with effective interpersonal skills.
- · Always willing and excited to continue the development of my knowledge and understanding. I always take this as a positive if that means a course or further qualifications.

Projects

Name	Description	Tech/tools
Portfolio website	place to host my CV and projects with links to projects that are currently live.	Next.js, Cypress and TailwindCss
ReefRunner	a side scroller game	JS, Phaser.js and Html canvas
AceBook	Social media application based off Facebook.	Node, Express, Jest, Nodemon, Hbs, Mongoosedb and Cypress
Tasks app -frontEnd Tasks app - Backend	a dynamic single page web app for planning events setting goals	Node, Express, Jest, MongoDB and Nodemon
Makers BnB	A Room listing and booking site	Sinatra, Rackup, Rspec, PostgreSQL, Tableplus and Bootstrap

Experience

Albany Beck Pionner Progam

A 12 week program preparing candidates for deployment in the finance industry:

- . Developed industry standards skills and methodologies/technologies such as Java OOP, JIRA and Confluence.
- . Six weeks dedicated to java development covering topics such as Spring Framework, Java Collections, data types and Exception handling.
- . SQL and Database concepts and design along with practical projects such as Event Management System project .
- . An introduction to Python along with its libraries such as Panda, Numpy and Math.plotlib.
- . Overview and practical use of devops tools such as Jenkins to create CID pipelines and AWS EC2 with Tomcat to host applications.
- . Built projects such as a full stack bookstore application, Bank Account application and Trading-OrderBook application using SpringBoot, micro services, TDD and SpingJPA.

Makers Academy (July 2022 to October 2022)

An intensive 16-week Bootcamp focusing on:

- Pairing to problem solve efficiently, requiring teamwork and communication.
- · Design concepts such as OOP, TDD, MVC and DDD.
- · We used these to deliver clean code. Practised through code-reviews, using SOLID Principles, i.e Single Responsibility
- For example principles like RAG, red, amber, and green allowed me to simple but effective code like in my bank tech test
- Agile Development process to build applications dynamically and quickly in a team. Using daily stand-ups and short sprints to keep our projects adaptable and quick to deploy this involved tools such as Trello, Miro, GitHub projects and Notion.
- · Learning strategies and fundamental concepts to allow for quick learning of various languages and technologies.

Royal Marines Recruit (April 2020 - March 2022)

- First applied in October 2019 but my application was delayed due to the covid lockdown.
- · Reapplied in 2020 and started the application process which involved passing:
 - · A gym fitness test
 - A PRMC (an intensive week of selections at the RM's training centre in Lympstone)
 - Started phase one of training on February 21st 2022.
 - Made section IC (in command) this meant I was responsible for my room of 9. I was required to meet with Corporals and Sergeants, to relay vital information back to my section and to insure orders were carried out correctly.
 - · Sustained a fractured shoulder socket after a rope climb which led to me being medically discharged.

Education:

Clayesmore School (2015 - 2018) - 9 GCSE grades achieved, 7 at grade 5 (C equivalent) or higher

· Science (Double Award) - 5 & 6, English Literature - 7, English Language - 6, Mathematics - 5 Computer Science - 6, Art - 7